<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Covid Papers</title>
    <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Covid Papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://covidpapers.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Italian study sheds light on asymptomatic transmission</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/suppression-of-covid-19-outbreak-in-the-municipality-of-vo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 20:48:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/suppression-of-covid-19-outbreak-in-the-municipality-of-vo-italy/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve long known that asymptomatic transmission was a thing and recently learned that pre-symptomatic viral loads are very high. A new preprint titled Suppression of COVID-19 outbreak in the municipality of Vo, Italy
A TL;DR below, but the big takeaway is that there was no significant difference in viral load between asymptomatic and symptomatic patients
🔥 Important (pre-print) study from Vo’, a small town in 🇮🇹, where most residents were tested (86% in 1st, 71% in 2nd survey)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some problems with the model US policymakers are using to forecast outbreak</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/caution-warranted-using-the-institute-for-health-metrics-and-evaluation-model-for-predicting-the-course-of-the-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 10:52:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/caution-warranted-using-the-institute-for-health-metrics-and-evaluation-model-for-predicting-the-course-of-the-covid-19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>A letter published in the Annals of Internal Medicine urges caution for policy makers relying on IHME&amp;rsquo;s model.
The TL;DR is captured by a statistician
Yet another important reminder, it doesn&amp;#39;t get clearer than this: &amp;quot;The IHME projections are based not on transmission dynamics but on a statistical model with no epidemiologic basis.&amp;quot; Fromhttps://t.co/BPO2j5bRvf
&amp;mdash; Leontine Alkema (@LeontineAlkema) April 15, 2020  You have probably seen this model before, it&amp;rsquo;s the one that gives graphs such as this</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New insights on when COVID-19 is most contagious</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/temporal-dynamics-in-viral-shedding-and-transmissibility-of-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 09:53:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/temporal-dynamics-in-viral-shedding-and-transmissibility-of-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>A study on viral shedding and transmissability was publshed in Nature today.
A couple of TL;DRs
Study of viral shedding in 94 #COVID19 cases, finding that infectiousness peaked up to 2 days before symptom onset, and that 44% of secondary cases were infected when the index cases were pre-symptomatic. Active case-finding crucial. #SARSCoV2 #HCoV19 https://t.co/AjUnmMU1nR
&amp;mdash; Dr Zoë Hyde (@DrZoeHyde) April 15, 2020  Latest research by @gmleunghku reports #COVID19 patients are most infectious in asymptomatic stage,i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early NYC cases fueled by multiple introductions from diverse origins. Community spread mainly linked to European and domestic introductions.</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/introductions-and-early-spread-of-sars-cov-2-in-the-new-york-city-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 12:59:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/introductions-and-early-spread-of-sars-cov-2-in-the-new-york-city-area/</guid>
      <description>A picture is emerging of early coronavirus transmission in NYC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next stop, phase 3 clinical trials: &#34;hopeful&#34; results from Remdesivir study released today</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/remdesivir-clinical-trial-result/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 15:33:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/remdesivir-clinical-trial-result/</guid>
      <description>Just published in the NEJM.
Big for #COVID19 therapy: the compassionate use results for remdesivir in 53 patients looks very encouraging, especially in very sick patients on mechanical ventilation with 18% fatality (only, expect &amp;gt; 50%) and overall 68% improvement https://t.co/oP8eDK6jYL @NEJM pic.twitter.com/9kisPxy1un
&amp;mdash; Eric Topol (@EricTopol) April 10, 2020  Key findings
 53 patients (initially 61, 1 excluded to a dosing error and 7 with no post-treatment data) 17 of 30 patients on ventilation were extubated 3 or 4 patients on ECMO stopped receiving it &amp;ldquo;clinical improvement was observed in 36 of 53 patients (68%)&amp;rdquo; 25 of 53 were discharged 7 of 53 died 23% had one or more serious adverse events  Study participants were given a 10-day course of Remdesivir: an IV loading dose of 200mg and 100mg daily the following 9 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent study on antibodies widely misinterpreted on re-infection and vaccine implications</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/neutralizing-antibody-responses-to-sars-cov-2-in-a-covid-19-recovered-1-patient-cohort-and-their-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:44:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/neutralizing-antibody-responses-to-sars-cov-2-in-a-covid-19-recovered-1-patient-cohort-and-their-implications/</guid>
      <description>You may have seen this recent headline from the South China Morning Post
This was passed around widely as a troubling sign
This is very worrisome. Among recovered former #COVID19 cases, “nearly a third had unexpectedly low levels of antibodies. In some cases, antibodies could not be detected at all.” 🤔 https://t.co/VEwTJWOJD2
&amp;mdash; Eric Feigl-Ding (@DrEricDing) April 8, 2020  However, &amp;ldquo;worrisome&amp;rdquo; was not even a good read of the results</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Moistly: A new study investigates whether SARS-CoV-2 could be transmitted via speech droplets</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/could-sars-cov-2-be-transmitted-via-speech-droplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:06:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/could-sars-cov-2-be-transmitted-via-speech-droplets/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the NIH and the University of Pennsylvania have put up a preprint titled Could SARS-CoV-2 be transmitted via speech droplets?
They write
 Considering that reports of asymptomatic transmission account for 50-80% of COVID-19 cases, droplet emission while speaking could be a significant factor driving transmission.
 They point to the high upper respiratory viral loads that have been documented elsewhere to support this idea.
Using laser light-scattering, they recorded the number of expelled droplets detected when volunteers said &amp;lsquo;stay healthy&amp;rsquo; 3 times in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is Coronavirus affected by weather? New study claims an association</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/evidence-that-higher-temperatures-are-associated-with-lower-incidence-of-covid-19-in-pandemic-state-cumulative-cases-reported-up-to-march-27-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 23:34:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/evidence-that-higher-temperatures-are-associated-with-lower-incidence-of-covid-19-in-pandemic-state-cumulative-cases-reported-up-to-march-27-2020/</guid>
      <description>In a new paper, Colorado researchers look at the possibility of a correlation between Covid and air temperature.
Looking at WHO case reports and building statistical models, they find
 significant reduction of case rates with mean maximum temperature above approximately 22.5 C or 72.5 F
 In the figure below the x-axis shows the mean temperature while the red bars show case count vs the dashed line which shows total population in that mean temperature bin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key findings from the largest ICU case study to date, just released: 1591 Covid Patients in Lombardy</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/1591-covid-patients-in-lombardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 21:14:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/1591-covid-patients-in-lombardy/</guid>
      <description>A study was just published describing 1591 ICU Covid patients in Lombardy, Italy, the largest study of its kind so far.
Annotations by @PulmCrit
Some key stats:
 82% of the patients were male median age was 63 years 68% had at least one comorbidity, with hypertension being the most common 88% of the patients for which there was this kind of data were intubated (1150 total) 58% remain in the ICU 16% have been discharged from the ICU 26% died during the study median length of stay of those who died in the ICU was 7 days median length of stay for those who were discharged from the ICU was 8 days  @PulmCrit speculates about metabolic syndrome comorbidities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New analysis estimates hidden spread in Washington state in January and February</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/cryptic-transmission-of-sars-cov-2-in-washington-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 16:39:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/cryptic-transmission-of-sars-cov-2-in-washington-state/</guid>
      <description>Trevor Bedford and 55 colleagues just published a preprint detailing some detective work on early transmission of Covid in Washington state.
The TL;DR is they looked at 346 viral genomes from infected patients and said the data are
 strongly suggesting cryptic spread of COVID-19during the months of January and February 2020, before active community surveillance was implemented.
 How they can know Bedford describes the way this detective work is done in a blog post but the gist is that viruses mutate all the time (often in ways that don&amp;rsquo;t effect function).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats the Deal with Hydroxychloroquine? The current state of scientific knowledge.</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/whats-the-deal-with-hydroxychloroquine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 23:53:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/whats-the-deal-with-hydroxychloroquine/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick look at what the science says today about Hydroxychloroquine or HCQ.
A recent letter in the Annals of Internal Medicine offers a TL;DR
 Data to support the use of HCQ and CQ for COVID-19 are limited and inconclusive.
 The French Study If you&amp;rsquo;ve heard anything at all about HCQ, it&amp;rsquo;s probably in some way related to this French study which came out without peer review in mid March.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: COVID Virus can survive up to 7 days on a mask. New data from The Lancet on virus stability at different temperatures, on different surfaces, and vs different disinfectants</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stability-of-sars-cov-2-in-different-environmental-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:36:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stability-of-sars-cov-2-in-different-environmental-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Alex W H Chin, Julie T S Chu, Mahen R A Perera, Kenrie P Y Hui, Hui-Ling Yen, Michael C W Chan, Malik Peiris, Leo L M Poon, Stability of SARS-CoV-2 in different environmental conditions, The Lancet Microbe, 2020,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Knowledge Base - Cases</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-cases/</guid>
      <description>3-day rolling average new cases by country graph  Daily cases per million people map  Total cases per million people map  Total cases per million people by country graph  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Knowledge Base - Deaths</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-deaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-deaths/</guid>
      <description>3-day rolling average new deaths by country graph  Daily deaths per million people map  Deaths per million people map  Total deaths by country graph  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Knowledge Base - Tests</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-testing/</guid>
      <description>Total tests by country  Tests per million people by country  Daily tests by country  Daily tests per million people by country </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rundown: Multiyear Mask Study Concludes Surgical Masks Could Prevent Transmission of Coronaviruses and Influenza</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/rundown-muli-year-mask-study-concludes-surgical-masks-could-prevent-transmission-of-coronaviruses-and-influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 18:55:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/rundown-muli-year-mask-study-concludes-surgical-masks-could-prevent-transmission-of-coronaviruses-and-influenza/</guid>
      <description>New results from scientists who had recently argued for more masking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Your Typical ARDS: the high-stakes debate about ICU Covid intubation</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/not-your-typical-ards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 01:41:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/not-your-typical-ards/</guid>
      <description>To ARDSnet or not to ARDSnet, that is the question</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Sputum and Feces After Conversion of Pharyngeal Samples</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/sars-cov-2positive-sputum-and-feces-after-conversion-of-pharyngeal-samples-in-patients-with-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:32:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/sars-cov-2positive-sputum-and-feces-after-conversion-of-pharyngeal-samples-in-patients-with-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Chen C, Gao G, Xu Y, et al. SARS-CoV-2–Positive Sputum and Feces After Conversion of Pharyngeal Samples in Patients With COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2020; [Epub ahead of print 30 March 2020]. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-0991&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7326/M20-0991&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an American with an MS in bioinformatics who has been following the Coronavirus outbreak since January.
My goal is to post digestible summaries of academic papers on COVID-19, along with some curated expert commentary.
Long term, I plan to keep an up-to-date dashboard of the current state of knowledge about the virus itself, the disease it causes, the public health response, and treatments and diagnostics coming out of the scientific literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case series in NEJM - early US ICU experience with COVID19 out of Seattle. 24 patients admitted with respiratory failure, most requiring vasopressor support. Mortality a striking 50% with 7 patients still hospitalized at press</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/covid-19-in-critically-ill-patients-in-the-seattle-region-case-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 11:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/covid-19-in-critically-ill-patients-in-the-seattle-region-case-series/</guid>
      <description>Covid-19 in Critically Ill Patients in the Seattle Region — Case Series</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A substantial portion of US healthcare workers are 55 years of age or older</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/older-clinicians-and-the-surge-in-novel-coronavirus-disease-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 02:07:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/older-clinicians-and-the-surge-in-novel-coronavirus-disease-2019/</guid>
      <description>Buerhaus PI, Auerbach DI, Staiger DO. Older Clinicians and the Surge in Novel Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA. Published online March 30, 2020. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.4978</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/covid19-trials/</guid>
      <description>Study Location Interventions Start date End date     Various Combination of Protease Inhibitors, Oseltamivir, Favipiravir, and Hydroxychloroquine for Treatment of COVID19 : A Randomized Control Trial Bangkok Thailand Lopinavir and Ritonavir Oseltamivir moderate to severe COVID19, Darunavir and Ritonavir plus oseltamivir, Favipiravir lopinavir /Ritonavir for mod. To severe, Oseltamivir plus Chloroquine in Mild COVID19, Darunavir /ritonavir oseltamivir chloroquine mod-severe, Lopinavir and Ritonavir plus Oseltamivir in mild COVID19, Darunavir /ritonavir favipiravir chloroquine mod-severe March 15, 2020 November 30, 2020   Pre-Exposure Prophylaxis With Hydroxychloroquine for High-Risk Healthcare Workers During the COVID-19 Pandemic Barcelona Spain Control group with placebo, Pre-exposure prophylaxis of SARS-CoV-2 April 3, 2020 October 30, 2020   The PATCH Trial (Prevention And Treatment of COVID-19 With Hydroxychloroquine) Philadelphia United States Cohort 2 HCQ high dose, Cohort 1 Placebo, Cohort 1 HCQ, Cohort 2 HCQ low dose, Cohort 3 Placebo, Cohort 3 HCQ April 6, 2020 December 1, 2021   Clinical Trial on Regularity of TCM Syndrome and Differentiation Treatment of COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>