<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>epidemiology on Covid Papers</title>
    <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/categories/epidemiology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in epidemiology on Covid Papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 14:44:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://covidpapers.github.io/categories/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford study showing widespread infection in Santa Clara county has many problems</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stanford-serology-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 14:44:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stanford-serology-study/</guid>
      <description>You probably saw the headline
related to a recent preprint. The conclusion that many have drawn is that we can conclude that COVID-19 is far less deadly than believed. However, the study is flawed in many ways.
Stanford Serology study preprint just posted that is certain to mislead many people:https://t.co/eitVtfjYoP
It&amp;#39;s a serological study, which is fantastic. We need these kinds of studies and data badly. Unfortunately this paper is badly misleading (bordering on purposeful?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early NYC cases fueled by multiple introductions from diverse origins. Community spread mainly linked to European and domestic introductions.</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/introductions-and-early-spread-of-sars-cov-2-in-the-new-york-city-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 12:59:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/introductions-and-early-spread-of-sars-cov-2-in-the-new-york-city-area/</guid>
      <description>A picture is emerging of early coronavirus transmission in NYC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key findings from the largest ICU case study to date, just released: 1591 Covid Patients in Lombardy</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/1591-covid-patients-in-lombardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 21:14:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/1591-covid-patients-in-lombardy/</guid>
      <description>A study was just published describing 1591 ICU Covid patients in Lombardy, Italy, the largest study of its kind so far.
Annotations by @PulmCrit
Some key stats:
 82% of the patients were male median age was 63 years 68% had at least one comorbidity, with hypertension being the most common 88% of the patients for which there was this kind of data were intubated (1150 total) 58% remain in the ICU 16% have been discharged from the ICU 26% died during the study median length of stay of those who died in the ICU was 7 days median length of stay for those who were discharged from the ICU was 8 days  @PulmCrit speculates about metabolic syndrome comorbidities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New analysis estimates hidden spread in Washington state in January and February</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/cryptic-transmission-of-sars-cov-2-in-washington-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 16:39:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/cryptic-transmission-of-sars-cov-2-in-washington-state/</guid>
      <description>Trevor Bedford and 55 colleagues just published a preprint detailing some detective work on early transmission of Covid in Washington state.
The TL;DR is they looked at 346 viral genomes from infected patients and said the data are
 strongly suggesting cryptic spread of COVID-19during the months of January and February 2020, before active community surveillance was implemented.
 How they can know Bedford describes the way this detective work is done in a blog post but the gist is that viruses mutate all the time (often in ways that don&amp;rsquo;t effect function).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>