<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>prevention on Covid Papers</title>
    <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/categories/prevention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in prevention on Covid Papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 20:48:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://covidpapers.github.io/categories/prevention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Italian study sheds light on asymptomatic transmission</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/suppression-of-covid-19-outbreak-in-the-municipality-of-vo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 20:48:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/suppression-of-covid-19-outbreak-in-the-municipality-of-vo-italy/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve long known that asymptomatic transmission was a thing and recently learned that pre-symptomatic viral loads are very high. A new preprint titled Suppression of COVID-19 outbreak in the municipality of Vo, Italy
A TL;DR below, but the big takeaway is that there was no significant difference in viral load between asymptomatic and symptomatic patients
🔥 Important (pre-print) study from Vo’, a small town in 🇮🇹, where most residents were tested (86% in 1st, 71% in 2nd survey)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New insights on when COVID-19 is most contagious</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/temporal-dynamics-in-viral-shedding-and-transmissibility-of-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 09:53:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/temporal-dynamics-in-viral-shedding-and-transmissibility-of-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>A study on viral shedding and transmissability was publshed in Nature today.
A couple of TL;DRs
Study of viral shedding in 94 #COVID19 cases, finding that infectiousness peaked up to 2 days before symptom onset, and that 44% of secondary cases were infected when the index cases were pre-symptomatic. Active case-finding crucial. #SARSCoV2 #HCoV19 https://t.co/AjUnmMU1nR
&amp;mdash; Dr Zoë Hyde (@DrZoeHyde) April 15, 2020  Latest research by @gmleunghku reports #COVID19 patients are most infectious in asymptomatic stage,i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Moistly: A new study investigates whether SARS-CoV-2 could be transmitted via speech droplets</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/could-sars-cov-2-be-transmitted-via-speech-droplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:06:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/could-sars-cov-2-be-transmitted-via-speech-droplets/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the NIH and the University of Pennsylvania have put up a preprint titled Could SARS-CoV-2 be transmitted via speech droplets?
They write
 Considering that reports of asymptomatic transmission account for 50-80% of COVID-19 cases, droplet emission while speaking could be a significant factor driving transmission.
 They point to the high upper respiratory viral loads that have been documented elsewhere to support this idea.
Using laser light-scattering, they recorded the number of expelled droplets detected when volunteers said &amp;lsquo;stay healthy&amp;rsquo; 3 times in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: COVID Virus can survive up to 7 days on a mask. New data from The Lancet on virus stability at different temperatures, on different surfaces, and vs different disinfectants</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stability-of-sars-cov-2-in-different-environmental-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 11:36:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/stability-of-sars-cov-2-in-different-environmental-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Alex W H Chin, Julie T S Chu, Mahen R A Perera, Kenrie P Y Hui, Hui-Ling Yen, Michael C W Chan, Malik Peiris, Leo L M Poon, Stability of SARS-CoV-2 in different environmental conditions, The Lancet Microbe, 2020,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rundown: Multiyear Mask Study Concludes Surgical Masks Could Prevent Transmission of Coronaviruses and Influenza</title>
      <link>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/rundown-muli-year-mask-study-concludes-surgical-masks-could-prevent-transmission-of-coronaviruses-and-influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 18:55:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://covidpapers.github.io/posts/rundown-muli-year-mask-study-concludes-surgical-masks-could-prevent-transmission-of-coronaviruses-and-influenza/</guid>
      <description>New results from scientists who had recently argued for more masking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>